# Rapolu Aniketh Vardhan

## Student at Hyderabad Institute of Technology and Management

Hyderabad, Telangana, India | rapoluav12@gmail.com | +91 863-921-6174 | anikethvardhan.netlify.app linkedin.com/in/aniketh-vardhan-rapolu | github.com/aniketh0418

### About Me

I am a passionate and highly motivated tech enthusiast with a keen interest in Computer Science - Data Science. Throughout my academic journey, I have honed my problem-solving skills and developed a knack for innovation. With a track record of collaborating effectively in team environments, whether it my field of expertise or not, depending to the requirements I develop my skills, while learning fastly is my special ability.

## **Education**

## **Hyderabad Institute of Technology and Management**, B.tech in Computer Science Engineering - Data Science | CGPA: 9.13

2022 - Present

Vision Junior College, Intermediate in Maths, Physics, and Chemistry

2020 - 2022

CGPA: 9.8

Amrita Vidyalayam, Schooling - CBSE

2022

CGPA: 8.6

## **Experience**

Software Support Analyst, KEPHI INNOVATIONS Pvt. Ltd.

April 2023 - June 2024

- Data Management and Analysis: Managed huge amount of user data fed into the integrated software, ultimately enhancing the user experience and operational efficiency.
- **Testing and Problem Solving:** Performed software testing to ensure seamless functionality, identified and reported malfunctions.

Market Research Analyst, HappiMynd

July 2023 - August 2023

- Research and Analysis: Analyzed market trends and provided insights for product development and enhancement.
- **Strategic Thinking:** Recommended solutions to improve the product by addressing issues encountered during usage, enhancing customer satisfaction and product performance.

#### **Publications**

Enhancing Project-Based Learning through Technology: A Generalized Approach to Managing Key Research Areas in Higher Education

June 2024

DOI:10.46647/ijetms.2024.v08i03.034 ISSIN: 2581-4621

## **Projects**

- Website to Visualize CSV Data: https://github.com/aniketh0418/CSV-Data-Visualization-Website.git
- Prototyped Wikipedia website with personalized UI settings: https://github.com/aniketh0418/wikipedia-contribution-webapp.git
- Omni-Mart (E-Commerce Website with Virtual Human Assistance): https://github.com/aniketh0418/Omni-Mart.git
- Attendance Automation with Notification System (Whatsapp): https://github.com/aniketh0418/Attendance-Automation-with-GUI.git

## Certifications

#### Virtual Job Simulation: Excel Skills for Business

Goldman Sachs via Forage

 Enhanced proficiency in Excel for business applications, focusing on data manipulation and analysis in MS Excel.

## Advanced Python: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn and Scipy for Data Analysis and Visualization

**Infosys Springborad** 

 Comprehensive training in essential Python libraries for data analysis and visualization.

#### Virtual Job Simulation: Data Analysis and Visualization

Accenture via Forage

 Applied data analytical techniques on big data that involved Data Modeling, Data Cleaning, Data Analysis, and Data Visualization to draw certain insights as required in a virtually simulated professional environment.

Power BI

Ministry of Micro, Small, and Medium Enterprises (MSME)

 Learned to create data-driven visualizations and business intelligence reports using Power BI.

Introduction to IoT

Ministry of Micro, Small, and Medium Enterprises (MSME)

• Acquired Knowledge of IoT fundamentals and applications.

## **Introduction to Web Developement**

GDSC

• Gained Fundamental skills and knowledge on Web Development.

## **Dialog Flow - Conversational AI**

GDSC

 Gained knowledge on building and deploying conversational AI and developed a Conversational AI chat-bot using Google Dialog Flow and Google Cloud.

## **Introduction to Flutter**

GDSC

• Gained an introduction to Andriod App Development using Flutter and built an Attendance Tracking App named ClassCount in flutter.

## **Entrepreneurial Thinking**

IUCEE

 Learned and gained insights on how to start a company and establish a start-up, understood basic fundamentals required to begin a start-up and acquired knowledge on legal permissions, BMC, and funding.

## **Introduction to Emerging Technologies**

**IUCEE** 

• Developed an understanding of the cutting-edge technologies.

#### Achievements

- Secured 1st place at Epithon (2023) and Qualified for INEX India International Project Expo. (2024). Epithon is a National Level Hackathon conducted by Shetty Group of Institutions held in kalaburagi, Karanataka.
- Secured 2nd place at Hack-O-Mania (2023). Hack-O-Mania is a National Level Hackathon organized by Vidya Jyothi Institute of Technology, in collaboration with GDSC-VJIT and Hack2Skill, held in Hyderabad, Telangana.
- Secured 3rd place at National Science Day Project Expo. (2023). An annual academic project expo. conducted by HITAM on National Science Day held in Hyderabad, Telangana.
- Secured 1st place at Indo Universal Collaboration for Engineering Education XPLORE Porject Expo. (2022). A project expo. conducted by IUCEE HITAM chapter at HITAM held in Hyderabad, Telangana.
- Received Special Appreciation Reward at Hack Your Path 4.0 (2022). Hack Your Path 4.0 is the 4th annual academic Hackathon conducted by HITAM HACKATHON Club at HITAM held in Hyderabad, Telangana.

## **Additional Experience And Positions**

## **GDG** on Campus Organizer at HITAM

2024 - Present

- **Tech Event Management:** Organized and led tech events and workshops, boosting campus engagement with emerging technologies.
- **Team Collaboration:** Worked with peers to deliver impactful tech initiatives and hands-on coding sessions.
- **Knowledge Sharing:** Facilitated learning on Data Science, machine learning, web development, Google Cloud and Android Development through sessions and workshops.

#### Lead at HITAM HACKATHON CLUB

2023 - 2024

- Event Leadership and External Participation: Led the planning and execution of campus hackathons, driving student participation and innovation. Participated in other Inter-state and National Hackathons.
- **Industry Collaboration:** Coordinated with industry sponsors and mentors to enhance event quality and networking opportunities.
- **Mentorship:** Provided guidance on project development and presentation skills to hackathon participants.

## Additional Accomplishments and Volunteering

- Organized Hack Your Path 5.0 a National Level HITAM annual Hackathon 2023, Novathon A "Hack-to-Hier" themed hackathon - 2024 and SIH Internal Hackathon at HITAM - 2024 as a part of the Core committee member of HITAM HACKATHON CLUB - HHC.
- Organized a National Technical Fest named 'INNOFIESTA-2K23' at HITAM as the lead of the Robotics Team. As a part of the IUCEE-EWB HITAM Chapter.
- Volunteered as one of the college representatives at 'Startup Pitching' and 'Project Expo' conducted at T-HUB, Hyderabad by TETA in collaboration with WTITC.

## **Skills**

**Programming and Scripting Languages:** C - Intermediate, Python - Advanced, SQL - Intermediate, HTML - Intermediate, CSS - Intermediate, JavaScript - Beginner

**Hard Skills:** MS Excel - Advanced, MS Word - Advanced, MS PowerPoint - Intermediate, Power BI - Intermediate, VS Code - Intermediate, Google Dialog Flow - Intermediate, Twilio - Beginner, Trulience - Beginner, Canva (UI/UX) - Intermediate

**Soft Skills:** Critical Thinking, Analytical Thinking, Problem Solving, leadership, Communication, Teamwork, Time Management, Multi-Tasking, Creativity, Content Writing, Presentation